<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Public Procurement on OKF</title>
    <link>https://okfn.de/tags/public-procurement/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Public Procurement on OKF</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>de</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 29 Jan 2018 07:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://okfn.de/tags/public-procurement/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Live Launch in Brüssel: Opentender.eu geht online </title>
      <link>https://okfn.de/blog/2018/01/big-data-with-local-impact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jan 2018 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://okfn.de/blog/2018/01/big-data-with-local-impact/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Heute geht das Vergabeportal &lt;a href=&#34;https://opentender.eu&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;opentender.eu&lt;/a&gt;, mit Datensätzen aus 32 Ländern und der Europäischen Kommission, online. Opentender.eu bietet die Möglichkeit Vergabedaten strukturiert einzusehen und zu visualisieren. Risikoindikatoren informieren zusätzlich über die Effizienz und Transparenz von Ausschreibungen.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Im Rahmen der &lt;a href=&#34;https://digiwhist.eu&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;DIGIWHIST&lt;/a&gt; Abschlusskonferenz &amp;ldquo;Big data with local impact: Using open data to improve public procurement&amp;rdquo; wird das Portal erstmalig der Öffentlichkeit vorgestellt. Die Konferenz kann per &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCAkFWKJ5L2LLM42o2mOxK3A/live&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Live-Stream&lt;/a&gt; verfolgt werden.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>From Publication to Award - The story of the missing information in the tender cycle</title>
      <link>https://okfn.de/blog/2016/07/from-publication-to-award/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Jul 2016 17:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://okfn.de/blog/2016/07/from-publication-to-award/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Billions of euros are spent on procuring for public goods. &lt;a href=&#34;http://digiwhist.eu/publications/towards-a-comprehensive-mapping-of-information-on-public-procurement-tendering-and-its-actors-across-europe/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Our research&lt;/a&gt; shows that some of the procurement could be done more efficient and hence cheaper. Here, having information on the whole public procurement cycle is essential to evaluate the process and monitor it properly. Without information on contract implementation such as the final price paid and completion date, any assessment is incomplete hence can be misleading.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;When most of the people think about public procurement they either think of the result (e.g. a highway or school being built) or the tender that they saw being announced. However, there is much more to it. Procurement processes sometimes span over long time periods and entail different stages. These stages usually include a call for expression of interest or pre-announcement; a formal call for tenders; announcements on modifications (if any); cancellations or clarifications of the calls (if any); announcements of the winning bidder(s) and details of the contract signature; and information on contract completion and assessment of companies’ performance during implementation. We exclude planning stages here, which are internal procedures and not published openly. &lt;strong&gt;While information on the full procurement process is crucial to assess its quality, publicly available information typically has considerable gaps in Europe.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Who has won the contract? - Identifying the bidders of public procurement processes</title>
      <link>https://okfn.de/blog/2016/06/who-has-won-the-contract/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2016 17:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://okfn.de/blog/2016/06/who-has-won-the-contract/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In the last couple of years there has been a strong push by political leaders and civil society towards making beneficial ownership more transparent. There are various very good reasons for this, varying from making it more difficult to disguising the beneficiary of transactions, or using shell companies for illicit purposes such as money laundering and hiding stolen assets. In the arena of public procurement there is the suggestion to start by publishing beneficial ownership for bidders for public tenders. We applaud this but we do not think this is enough. To be able to trace where public money goes, prevent collusion in public procurement, and track organisational performance more broadly the most important prerequisite is to have &lt;strong&gt;unique identifiers for both bidders and buyers.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Public procurement in Europe needs to enter the digital era</title>
      <link>https://okfn.de/blog/2016/03/public-procurement-digital-era/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://okfn.de/blog/2016/03/public-procurement-digital-era/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Approximately 20% of the EU’s GDP every year is spent on procuring public goods and some estimate that the costs added to government contracts due to corruption amount to around 20-25%. This is a striking amount and it is even more worrying considering that it compromises widely supported public goals such a building safe highways, high quality school buildings, or delivering medicine for a fair price. This is one of the main reasons why more research needs to be done to make public procurement more efficient and transparent. Addressing this gap is what this new EU-funded large-scale project, &lt;a href=&#34;http://digiwhist.eu&#34;&gt;DIGIWHIST&lt;/a&gt;, does.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Open Knowledge Foundation Germany awarded H2020 project to improve transparency in public spending and support whistleblowing</title>
      <link>https://okfn.de/blog/2015/01/okfde-awarded-h2020-project-to-improve-transparency-in-public-spending-and-support-whistleblowing/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2015 17:25:23 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://okfn.de/blog/2015/01/okfde-awarded-h2020-project-to-improve-transparency-in-public-spending-and-support-whistleblowing/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Horizon 2020 project DIGIWHIST to build a digital whistleblowing platform and help improve transparency in public spending&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Berlin – 25.01.2014 – The tell-tale signs of public spending gone wrong are easy to spot. For example, an airport that is many years behind schedule and billions of Euro over budget, or a highway which leads to nowhere. What has been harder up to now is to how to shine a light on the problem and engage civil society in helping to curb it. The Open Knowledge Foundation Germany has just been awarded a new&lt;a href=&#34;http://ec.europa.eu/programmes/horizon2020/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt; Horizon 2020&lt;/a&gt; research project, DIGIWHIST, which aims to do just that.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
