<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>OGDCamp on OKF</title>
    <link>https://okfn.de/tags/ogdcamp/</link>
    <description>Recent content in OGDCamp on OKF</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>de</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 15 Dec 2011 07:00:46 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://okfn.de/tags/ogdcamp/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>OGD Camp reloaded</title>
      <link>https://okfn.de/blog/2011/12/ogd-camp-reloaded/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Dec 2011 07:00:46 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://okfn.de/blog/2011/12/ogd-camp-reloaded/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Viele von euch waren sicherlich beim &lt;a href=&#34;http://ogdcamp.org&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Open Government Data Camp&lt;/a&gt; in Warschau dabei, einige wären gerne dagewesen, konnten aber nicht. Alle die da waren konnten sicherlich nicht alles ansehen und behalten was sie wollten.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In den letzten Wochen haben wir deshalb eifrig Daten gesammelt, Präsentationen und Bilder gesichtet und diese jetzt auf &lt;a href=&#34;http://ogdcamp.org/after/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;www.ogdcamp.org/after&lt;/a&gt; bereitgestellt.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;testimonials&#34;&gt;Testimonials&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;“Every community needs a big event to bring everyone together every year. Just like every family has a Christmas party, where all are welcome, regardless of what happened during the year. The OGD Camp is the open data community’s Christmas party. I can’t wait ’till next Christmas.”&lt;/em&gt; — Ton Zijlstra, &lt;a href=&#34;http://epsiplatform.eu/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;ePSIplatform.eu&lt;/a&gt;, Netherlands&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;“[I loved] the ‘gathering of the tribes’. It was wonderful to meet similar projects, the scholars, and the politicians supporting them. And the venue – the M25 was incredibly cool.”&lt;/em&gt; — Iván Sánchez, &lt;a href=&#34;http://openstreetmap.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Open Street Map&lt;/a&gt;, Spain&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;“I came to OGDCamp to meet people who were working with city government and were involved with changing perception of open practices in their own communities – and this is where I think the power of OGDCamp and similar events lie.”&lt;/em&gt; — Julian Tate,&lt;a href=&#34;http://futureeverything.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;FutureEverything&lt;/a&gt;, United Kingdom&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;“This year’s OGDCamp was really nice, from the venue to the talks, and included lots of reunions and new encounters. Meeting with lots of new parliamentary projects and having great discussions to… share ideas was really cool, and kind of reminded me of the former BerlinInOctober’s event!”&lt;/em&gt; — Benjamin Ooghe-Tabanou, &lt;a href=&#34;http://regardscitoyens.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Regards Citoyens&lt;/a&gt;, France&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;“I was happily surprised by the number of new people I met working on interesting projects in countries that, due to language barriers, I had heard less about in Canada. After the camp, I was able to connect these people with similar projects in my home country and abroad to share experiences and resources.”&lt;/em&gt; — James McKinney, &lt;a href=&#34;http://opennorth.ca/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Open North&lt;/a&gt;, Canada&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;“It was fun to meet the gang. This is wonderful project that you are involved with… we are creating ripples of change that hopefully will turn into tsunamis of open government data in the future.”&lt;/em&gt; — Bernadette Hyland, &lt;a href=&#34;http://3roundstones.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;3RoundStones Inc&lt;/a&gt;, USA&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;“This was a great chance to meet some of the most practical, effective re-users of open data out there, and a good forum to try to establish cooperation between international projects of similar kinds.”&lt;/em&gt; — Tom Steinberg, &lt;a href=&#34;http://mysociety.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;My Society&lt;/a&gt;, United Kingdom&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;videos&#34;&gt;Videos&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Es ist nicht sinnvoll hier die Videos von all den guten Präsentationen einzubinden. Ich habe einfach mal zwei herausgegriffen, die mir persönlich besonders gut gefallen haben. Außerdem gibt es eine Vielzahl von Videos von der Veranstaltung auf unserem &lt;a href=&#34;http://vimeo.com/okf/videos&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Vimeo Channel.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Registration for Open Government Data Camp 2011 is now open!</title>
      <link>https://okfn.de/blog/2011/08/registration-for-open-government-data-camp-2011-is-now-open/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Aug 2011 08:32:57 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://okfn.de/blog/2011/08/registration-for-open-government-data-camp-2011-is-now-open/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The following is a cross post from &lt;a href=&#34;http://jonathangray.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Jonathan Gray&lt;/a&gt;, Community Coordinator at the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.okfn.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Open Knowledge Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We’re delighted to announce that registration for &lt;a href=&#34;http://ogdcamp.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ogdcamp.org/register/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;You can find out more about the event here:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://ogdcamp.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://ogdcamp.org/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you’d like to know more about open government data, you can see our short &lt;a href=&#34;http://opengovernmentdata.org/film/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;#opendata film&lt;/a&gt;, which was shot at &lt;a href=&#34;http://opengovernmentdata.org/camp2010/after/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;last year’s camp&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
