<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Activism From Within on OKF</title>
    <link>https://okfn.de/tags/activism-from-within/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Activism From Within on OKF</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>de</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://okfn.de/tags/activism-from-within/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Menstrual Leave Policy</title>
      <link>https://okfn.de/blog/2026/01/menstrual-leave-policy/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://okfn.de/blog/2026/01/menstrual-leave-policy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;In many countries and companies, there is a debate about whether menstrual pain and cycle-related discomfort should be recognised as grounds for additional days off as part of a gender-equitable working environment.&lt;/strong&gt; Such regulations exist in some countries by law (e.g. in Japan, South Korea and Taiwan) and voluntarily in many companies. &lt;strong&gt;We have had this model in place since 2021, anchored in our Menstrual Leave Policy. We spoke to Sonja Fischbauer, our organisational developer, about it.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dealing with conflicts – A guide to routinely resolving tensions within the team</title>
      <link>https://okfn.de/blog/2025/09/dealing-with-conflicts-a-guide-to-routinely-resolving-tensions-within-the-team/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://okfn.de/blog/2025/09/dealing-with-conflicts-a-guide-to-routinely-resolving-tensions-within-the-team/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;In this article, we share our first version of a conflict routine: a guide on how to proceed when you find yourself in a conflict.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It is easy to let everyone participate when everything is running smoothly. It gets harder when tensions arise. That is precisely when it becomes clear whether our values hold true in everyday life. If we are committed to a democratic, sustainable and resilient future, we must also create internal spaces where conflicts can be addressed, endured and resolved. Conflicts can be an opportunity for personal growth, better cooperation and structural development.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Uncovering power structures – An exercise for talking about power</title>
      <link>https://okfn.de/blog/2025/09/uncovering-power-structures-an-exercise-for-talking-about-power/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://okfn.de/blog/2025/09/uncovering-power-structures-an-exercise-for-talking-about-power/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;In this article, we share instructions for an exercise we developed to facilitate conversations about power structures in our organisation.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;For a democratic, sustainable and resilient future, we demand transparency, participation and cooperation on an equal footing from politicians. In our organisation, we strive to not only represent these values externally, but also to live them internally.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It is important to talk openly and calmly about power structures so that we can fulfil our demands for transparency and justice internally. This is an honourable approach, but one that is often difficult to implement in practice. Even if we have flat, transparent hierarchies, unspoken power relations and routines will form outside the official channels. The less they are addressed, the more entrenched they become. We must review formal structures to ensure that they have sufficient counterbalances and control mechanisms. We must recognise and name informal power so that it is not distributed unfairly.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Developing decision-making structures - How we organise our collaboration</title>
      <link>https://okfn.de/blog/2025/09/developing-decision-making-structures-how-we-organise-our-collaboration/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://okfn.de/blog/2025/09/developing-decision-making-structures-how-we-organise-our-collaboration/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;In this article, we show how we organise ourselves internally. We describe the structures we use to promote co-determination and distribute power.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In our work, we strive for a democratic, sustainable and resilient future based on openness, participation and transparency. In order to live up to this aspiration within our organisation, we need to organise our internal collaboration accordingly: we need a solid governance model.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A governance model is a plan for how people in a group make decisions. It regulates questions such as: &lt;em&gt;Who is allowed to decide what? Who is responsible for what?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Activism from Within - Introduction</title>
      <link>https://okfn.de/blog/2025/09/activism-from-within-introduction/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://okfn.de/blog/2025/09/activism-from-within-introduction/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;NGOs and non-profit organisations are constantly working to bring about lasting change in society. OKF also works towards social justice and participation on many levels in its numerous projects. However, organisations often lack an inward perspective. With this new series, we want to provide transparency: &lt;em&gt;How do we make decisions? How do we distribute power? How do we shape collaboration?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://okfn.de/aktivismus-von-innen/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&amp;lsquo;Activism from Within&amp;rsquo;&lt;/a&gt; addresses precisely these issues.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Over the next three weeks, we will give you an insight into our structures and share experiences, challenges and tools for implementing our social demands internally.&#xA;In &lt;strong&gt;part 1&lt;/strong&gt;, we show how we organise ourselves internally. We describe the structures we use to promote co-determination and distribute power. In &lt;strong&gt;part 2&lt;/strong&gt;, we share instructions for an exercise we use to facilitate discussions about power structures in our organisation. And finally, in &lt;strong&gt;part 3&lt;/strong&gt;, we share our first version of a conflict routine: instructions on how to proceed when you find yourself in a conflict.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
