<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Germany on OKF</title>
    <link>https://okfn.de/tags/germany/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Germany on OKF</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>de</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 02 Aug 2017 10:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://okfn.de/tags/germany/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Germany finally has an Open Data Law</title>
      <link>https://okfn.de/blog/2017/08/germany-finally-has-an-open-data-law/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Aug 2017 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://okfn.de/blog/2017/08/germany-finally-has-an-open-data-law/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;On July 13, 2017 Germany’s first Open Data law came into effect, finally enabling free access to government data. The Open Data law is part of the change of the German E-Government law &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.gesetze-im-internet.de/egovg/__12a.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;(EGovG)&lt;/a&gt;, which we translated &lt;a href=&#34;https://okfn.de/blog/2017/07/Germany%27s-open-data-law-english/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. While it is neither part of the freedom of information act nor an actual transparency law, it provides the judicial foundation for obtaining data from all public authorities subject to the federal government. The authorities will provide raw data on publicly accessible networks, if it was stored in an electronically structured form and includes facts that regard circumstances outside of the administration. Furthermore, a central support agency for open data will be established.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>German Open Data Law in English</title>
      <link>https://okfn.de/blog/2017/07/germanys-open-data-law-english/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Jul 2017 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://okfn.de/blog/2017/07/germanys-open-data-law-english/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Disclaimer&lt;/em&gt;: we translated the German Open Data Law to make it accessible for the international Open Data community. This is &lt;strong&gt;not&lt;/strong&gt; an official legal translation, but we gave it our very best. The German version can be found below or &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.gesetze-im-internet.de/egovg/__12a.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2&gt; Law for the advancement of digital public administration &#xA;&#x9;(E-Government-Law - EGovG) &lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3&gt; § 12a Open Data for public authorities subordinate to the federal administration &lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(1) The public authorities subordinate to the federal administration will provide raw data, obtained fulfilling their public-law duties or through third parties, to be retrieved on publicly accessible networks. A claim for the provision of this data is not founded herewith.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
