<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Open Knowledge Foundation DE</title>
    <link rel="self" href="https://okfn.de/en/publikationen/atom.xml"/>
    <description>Publications on OKF DE</description>
    
    
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 28 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
        <atom:link href="https://okfn.de/en/publikationen/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>E-Government Act Brandenburg</title>
      <link>https://okfn.de/en/publikationen/2023_egovernment-brandenburg/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://okfn.de/en/publikationen/2023_egovernment-brandenburg/</guid>
      <description>The state government of Brandenburg wants to incorporate open data into the legal framework by amending the existing law. However, the OKF considers the proposed changes to be insufficient. In a short statement we outline several points of criticism.
The state government of Brandenburg is addressing oversights that occurred during the launch of the E-Government Act through this legislation. It establishes guidelines for making open data accessible, and the accompanying memorandum explicitly identifies open data as an objective.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Position on the Global Digital Compact of German Digital Civil Society Organizations</title>
      <link>https://okfn.de/en/publikationen/2023_globaldigitalcompact/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://okfn.de/en/publikationen/2023_globaldigitalcompact/</guid>
      <description>As part of the Global Digital Compact (GDC), the United Nations is working to shape the digital future on a global scale. In May 2023, the UN Secretary-General presented a policy brief on this issue. Governments are now positioning themselves and should listen to the voices of civil society. Over the past few weeks, the Open Knowledge Foundation, as part of an alliance of civil society organizations (on the initiative of Wikimedia Germany), has taken a closer look at the policy brief and made suggestions for desirable adjustments.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>F5 Alliance Press Release on the Digital Services Act (DSA)</title>
      <link>https://okfn.de/en/publikationen/2023_f5_pm_ddg/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://okfn.de/en/publikationen/2023_f5_pm_ddg/</guid>
      <description>Germany is at risk of losing the opportunity to bring internet platforms - such as social networks or online marketplaces - under effective, independent supervision. The Digital Services Act (DSA) aims to protect users&amp;rsquo; rights online and sets out due diligence obligations for platforms such as TikTok, Facebook and Twitter. In order to effectively achieve these goals, a centralized and well-organized platform supervisory authority in EU member states is needed to quickly and competently handle complaints from affected parties and enforce their rights.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Open Knowledge Foundation Germany e.V. - 2022 Annual report</title>
      <link>https://okfn.de/en/publikationen/2022-jahresbericht/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://okfn.de/en/publikationen/2022-jahresbericht/</guid>
      <description>The report looks back at the work of the Open Knowledge Foundation Germany in 2022. The report summarizes the most important activities, describes how the organization works, and presents all projects in brief. The final part of the annual report includes information on the organizational structure and finances.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The F5 Alliance on the Civic Engagement Strategy of the Federal Government</title>
      <link>https://okfn.de/en/publikationen/2023_f5_engagementstrategie/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://okfn.de/en/publikationen/2023_f5_engagementstrategie/</guid>
      <description>In this legislative period, a new federal strategy for civic engagement is to be developed with the participation of civil society. The last Civic Engagement Strategy dates back to 2010, so it&amp;rsquo;s about time - because a lot has happened! Digital volunteering has grown significantly and new technologies are increasingly permeating our lives.
As part of the official participation of associations, we have submitted a joint declaration of the F5 Alliance.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hesse Open Data Act (HODaG)</title>
      <link>https://okfn.de/en/publikationen/2023_stellungnahme-hessisches-opendatagesetz/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://okfn.de/en/publikationen/2023_stellungnahme-hessisches-opendatagesetz/</guid>
      <description>The provision of open data is a central element in the implementation of open government and a key prerequisite for transparency, accountability and verifiability of political actions, acceptance of political decisions, opinion formation and participation.
Although the Hessian government has taken the overdue first step with the Open Data Act, it is failing to draw the right conclusions from the numerous examples of other already existing open data laws. We have outlined our comments and criticisms in this statement.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>E-Government Act of Hesse</title>
      <link>https://okfn.de/en/publikationen/2023_stellungnahme-hessischen-e-government-gesetzes/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://okfn.de/en/publikationen/2023_stellungnahme-hessischen-e-government-gesetzes/</guid>
      <description>The draft law essentially deals with the implementation of the digital provision of administrative services in state law, which has become mandatory as a result of the Federal Law on Online Access (OZG).
In the view of the Open Knowledge Foundation Germany, the Hessian state government is implementing necessary changes in the area of user accounts and official mailboxes with the draft law, but is missing the opportunity, after more than four years, to formulate further-reaching regulations and objectives with a genuine amendment to the HEGovG as to how the digital transformation could contribute to an efficient and transparent administration.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Funding for Future</title>
      <link>https://okfn.de/en/publikationen/2022_handbuch-funding-for-future/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://okfn.de/en/publikationen/2022_handbuch-funding-for-future/</guid>
      <description>In this handbook, the Prototype Fund offers a case study of open source software to demonstrate how individuals and small teams can benefit from unbureaucratic funding. The handbook examines the advantages of such funding and provides insights into its workings.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sovereign Tech Fund - Feasibility Study</title>
      <link>https://okfn.de/en/publikationen/2021_sovereigntechfeasibility/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://okfn.de/en/publikationen/2021_sovereigntechfeasibility/</guid>
      <description>In the study the authors examined the needs and possibilities for a funding program to strengthen open digital infrastructure. The idea for a fund is based, among other things, on Open Technology Funds Core Infrastructure Fund and can learn from this and the experiences from other programs, e.g. the Prototype Fund, and adopt already tested procedures. For the design of the Sovereign Tech Fund, numerous other existing programs were analyzed, interviews were conducted with developers and stakeholders in the open source ecosystem, and expert workshops were held.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
