<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Open Knowledge Foundation DE</title>
  <link rel="self" href="https://okfn.de/en/finanzierung/atom.xml"/>
  <updated>0001-01-01T00:00:00+0000</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Open Knowledge Foundation DE</name>
    <email>info@okfn.de</email>
    <uri>https://okfn.de</uri>
  </author>
  <id>https://okfn.de</id>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Development of total revenue</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://okfn.de/en/finanzierung/entwicklung/"/>
    <id>https://okfn.de/en/finanzierung/entwicklung/</id>
    <published>0001-01-01T00:00:00+0000</published>
    <updated>0001-01-01T00:00:00+0000</updated>
    <summary> </summary>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Expenses 2021</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://okfn.de/en/finanzierung/ausgaben/"/>
    <id>https://okfn.de/en/finanzierung/ausgaben/</id>
    <published>0001-01-01T00:00:00+0000</published>
    <updated>0001-01-01T00:00:00+0000</updated>
    <summary>Personnel costs are by far the largest expense item. Our excellent team is our most important resource. In addition, non-personnel costs as well as tax payments are incurred every year. Most of the expenditure is project-related. We try to keep the administrative costs of the organization low. They include, for example, material costs for rent, finances, insurances and technical infrastructure.</summary>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Revenues 2021</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://okfn.de/en/finanzierung/einnahmen/"/>
    <id>https://okfn.de/en/finanzierung/einnahmen/</id>
    <published>0001-01-01T00:00:00+0000</published>
    <updated>0001-01-01T00:00:00+0000</updated>
    <summary>The majority (75%) of our income comes from project-related grants. In addition, there is growing donation income amounting to approximately 19% of our income. Most of the donations are addressed to FragDenStaat. Additionally, Jugend hackt, Code for Germany and OKF DE as a whole record donations. Furthermore, we generated about 6% of our income from economic income sources. Sponsoring currently accounts for less than 1% of our funds.
Overview Grants Sponsorship Income from contracts Donations *Organisation does not want to be named publicly, but may be disclosed upon inquiry Projects financed by individual donations or based on voluntary work Our projects emerge from a solution-oriented as well as idealistic attitude, and are often initiated by volunteer activities.</summary>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
