<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Community on OKF DE</title>
    <link>https://okfn.de/en/categories/community/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Community on OKF DE</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>de-DE</language>
    
	<atom:link href="https://okfn.de/en/categories/community/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Apps and the city</title>
      <link>https://okfn.de/en/projekte/appsandthecity/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://okfn.de/en/projekte/appsandthecity/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;Apps and the City&amp;rdquo; was a hackday on local traffic organised by Open Knowledge Foundation Germany together with the local transport provider VBB, the Berlin government, and the FH Potsdam. The VBB released GTFS data, opened up their API and provided some geo datasets about entrances to stations. During the event, coders, software experts, and designers used open transport data to create applications intended to improve public transport non-commercially.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Code for Germany</title>
      <link>https://okfn.de/en/projekte/codeforde/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://okfn.de/en/projekte/codeforde/</guid>
      <description>Code For Germany is a network of groups of volunteers (labs) who use their skills to shape their cities and social life. They advocate more transparency, open data and participation in their cities. In particular, they mediate between civil society, administration and politics, and use their skills to improve communication between them. This provides the necessary impetus so that as many people as possible can benefit from open and free digitisation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Energyhack</title>
      <link>https://okfn.de/en/projekte/energyhack/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://okfn.de/en/projekte/energyhack/</guid>
      <description>Energyhack is a hackathon around open energy data. Our energy supply and the ways of its generation are manifold. But how is energy distributed and how do we ensure that more information can be exchanged between producers and consumers? Together with developers, designers, and researchers, thought leaders in the energy industry brainstorm ideas, design, and develop prototypes in 24 hours. The data from the Open Data Portal Netzdaten-Berlin was available to the participants as a database.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FragDenStaat</title>
      <link>https://okfn.de/en/projekte/fragdenstaat/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://okfn.de/en/projekte/fragdenstaat/</guid>
      <description>In a democracy, it is necessary for citizens to be able to inform themselves freely about government actions. With the Freedom of Information Act, every person, regardless of age or origin, has the right to request documents from the authorities. The FragDenStaat online platform supports citizens in exercising their right to access information from German authorities. Citizens no longer have to work their way through the legal jungle of the federal states and the federal government to make a request.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jugend hackt</title>
      <link>https://okfn.de/en/projekte/jugendhackt/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://okfn.de/en/projekte/jugendhackt/</guid>
      <description>Jugend hackt is a program for young people who want to improve the world with their technical skills. Supported by volunteer mentors, our participants develop digital tools, prototypes and concepts for a better future. Our offer includes hackathon events in many cities, regional labs, an online community and international exchange programs.
In line with our motto &amp;ldquo;Improve the world with code&amp;rdquo;, Jugend hackt is about more than just learning to program: We understand technology as a means of social change.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Prototype Fund</title>
      <link>https://okfn.de/en/projekte/prototypefund/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://okfn.de/en/projekte/prototypefund/</guid>
      <description>The Prototype Fund supports socially relevant software projects and increases their sustainable impact by open sourcing as a principle. In short: We support Public Interest Tech.
We make digital-social innovation possible with developers that bring a wide range of skills in technology design. With up to 47,500 euros per project and team, the Prototype Fund supports software developers, hackers and creatives in building protptypes for tools and applications in the areas of civic tech, data literacy, IT security and software infrastructure.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>edulabs</title>
      <link>https://okfn.de/en/projekte/edulabs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://okfn.de/en/projekte/edulabs/</guid>
      <description>edulabs sees itself as a supra-regional incubator in which people use their didactic, technical, and creative skills to develop innovative and re-usable educational materials. The project works on three levels: concept development, provision and advertising of open educational resources as well as community building and support. Throughout Germany, edulabs organises meetings of interdisciplinary teams where open educational resources and digitally supported methods are evaluated, created, documented, and improved. The lab community is supported editorially, didactically, technically, as well as with the organisation of events.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>