<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Fiscal Transparency on OKF</title>
    <link>https://okfn.de/tags/fiscal-transparency/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Fiscal Transparency on OKF</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>de</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 15 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://okfn.de/tags/fiscal-transparency/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>From Publication to Award - The story of the missing information in the tender cycle</title>
      <link>https://okfn.de/blog/2016/07/from-publication-to-award/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://okfn.de/blog/2016/07/from-publication-to-award/</guid>
      <description>Billions of euros are spent on procuring for public goods. Our research shows that some of the procurement could be done more efficient and hence cheaper. Here, having information on the whole public procurement cycle is essential to evaluate the process and monitor it properly. Without information on contract implementation such as the final price paid and completion date, any assessment is incomplete hence can be misleading.&#xA;When most of the people think about public procurement they either think of the result (e.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Who has won the contract? - Identifying the bidders of public procurement processes</title>
      <link>https://okfn.de/blog/2016/06/who-has-won-the-contract/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://okfn.de/blog/2016/06/who-has-won-the-contract/</guid>
      <description>In the last couple of years there has been a strong push by political leaders and civil society towards making beneficial ownership more transparent. There are various very good reasons for this, varying from making it more difficult to disguising the beneficiary of transactions, or using shell companies for illicit purposes such as money laundering and hiding stolen assets. In the arena of public procurement there is the suggestion to start by publishing beneficial ownership for bidders for public tenders.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Public procurement in Europe needs to enter the digital era</title>
      <link>https://okfn.de/blog/2016/03/public-procurement-digital-era/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://okfn.de/blog/2016/03/public-procurement-digital-era/</guid>
      <description>Approximately 20% of the EU’s GDP every year is spent on procuring public goods and some estimate that the costs added to government contracts due to corruption amount to around 20-25%. This is a striking amount and it is even more worrying considering that it compromises widely supported public goals such a building safe highways, high quality school buildings, or delivering medicine for a fair price. This is one of the main reasons why more research needs to be done to make public procurement more efficient and transparent.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
