<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>United Nations on OKF</title>
    <link>https://okfn.de/tags/united-nations/</link>
    <description>Recent content in United Nations on OKF</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>de</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 16 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://okfn.de/tags/united-nations/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Global efforts to strengthen open source concepts – Insights from the OSPO conference at the United Nations</title>
      <link>https://okfn.de/blog/2024/07/ospo-en/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://okfn.de/blog/2024/07/ospo-en/</guid>
      <description>Last week, the second edition of the conference Open Source Programme Offices for Good (#OSPOsForGood) took place in New York. At the invitation of the United Nations (UN), around 450 open source enthusiasts from all over the world traveled to the event - a huge success for the organizers, as there were around 80 participants in 2023. It was about nothing less than the role of open source software in achieving the Sustainable Development Goals - i.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Globale Anstrengungen zur Stärkung von Open Source Ansätzen – Eindrücke von der OSPO-Konferenz bei den Vereinten Nationen</title>
      <link>https://okfn.de/blog/2024/07/ospo-deu/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://okfn.de/blog/2024/07/ospo-deu/</guid>
      <description>Letzte Woche fand die zweite Auflage der Konferenz Open Source Programme Offices for Good (#OSPOsForGood) in New York statt. Auf Einladung der Vereinten Nationen (UN) reisten etwa 450 Open-Source-Enthusiast:innen aus aller Welt an - ein Riesenerfolg für die Veranstalter:innen, waren es 2023 noch rund 80 Teilnehmende. Es ging um nichts weniger als die Rolle von Open Source Software für die Erreichung der Sustainable Development Goals - also Weltrettung, Kernaufgabe der UN.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
