<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Open Knowledge Foundation DE</title>
  <link rel="self" href="https://okfn.de/en/projekte/atom.xml"/>
  <updated>0001-01-01T00:00:00+0000</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Open Knowledge Foundation DE</name>
    <email>info@okfn.de</email>
    <uri>https://okfn.de</uri>
  </author>
  <id>https://okfn.de</id>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Bits &amp; Bäume</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://okfn.de/en/projekte/bits-und-baeume/"/>
    <id>https://okfn.de/en/projekte/bits-und-baeume/</id>
    <published>0001-01-01T00:00:00+0000</published>
    <updated>0001-01-01T00:00:00+0000</updated>
    <summary>&lt;p&gt;After the successful first Bits &amp;amp; Bäume Conference in 2018, the topics of digitalization and sustainability are more present in our society today than ever before. We are facing major societal and global challenges for a just and sustainable shaping of our (surrounding) world. Therefore, we would like to broaden and consolidate the networking of environmental and justice activists, technology experts and human rights activists with the &lt;strong&gt;Bits &amp;amp; Bäume 2022 conference from September 30 to October 2, 2022.&lt;/strong&gt; This also includes networking our communities with representatives of social-ecological small digital businesses and founders as well as politicians in order to find concrete solutions for the pressing issues of our time. We want to discuss major political strategies and governance proposals, but also learn from each other through best practice examples how we can realize climate and environmental protection, social justice, democracy and fundamental rights in the digital age.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Open Gov Netzwerk</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://okfn.de/en/projekte/ogp/"/>
    <id>https://okfn.de/en/projekte/ogp/</id>
    <published>0001-01-01T00:00:00+0000</published>
    <updated>0001-01-01T00:00:00+0000</updated>
    <summary>&lt;p&gt;As part of the Open Government Network, we support Germany&amp;rsquo;s active participation in the Open Government Partnership (OGP) and the interests of German civil society in this process, as well as help coordinate this civil society network.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The network is an association of civil society organisations and individuals that has been working since 2011 to promote open government and administrative action as a holistic approach to strengthening democracy. In particular, the focus is on the exchange with the Federal Government and the development of national action plans.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Turing-Bus</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://okfn.de/en/projekte/turing-bus/"/>
    <id>https://okfn.de/en/projekte/turing-bus/</id>
    <published>0001-01-01T00:00:00+0000</published>
    <updated>0001-01-01T00:00:00+0000</updated>
    <summary>&lt;p&gt;The Turing Bus is a mobile educational project for schools and youth clubs in rural areas. The bus brings representatives of Fablabs, OK-Labs and Hackspaces as well as experts in digital topics to often underserved places of youth education. Its goal is to generate an exchange of knowledge and experiences through workshops, discussions, screenings, and more. The project is funded in the &lt;a href=&#34;https://wissenschaftsjahr.de&#34;&gt;Science Year&lt;/a&gt; of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://bmbf.de&#34;&gt;BMBF&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Bus wants to explore, discuss, and critically question the role of digitisation and technology in the professional landscape and society as a whole. It engages young adults between the ages of 15 and 20 with workshops, lectures, as well as hands-on sessions.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Prototype Fund</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://okfn.de/en/projekte/prototypefund/"/>
    <id>https://okfn.de/en/projekte/prototypefund/</id>
    <published>0001-01-01T00:00:00+0000</published>
    <updated>0001-01-01T00:00:00+0000</updated>
    <summary>&lt;p&gt;With the Prototype Fund, we support socially relevant software projects and increase their sustainable impact through open source by principle. In short: We fund open source software made by society and for society.
We make digital social innovation possible with developers who bring a wide range of skills to technology design and are given the space to develop their good ideas. You will receive funding of up to €95,000 over six months or €158,000 over ten months for your project and team. The fund supports software developers, hackers, and creative minds in turning sketches for tools and applications into reality. The Prototype Fund has redefinied its funding priorities since 2025 and now focuses on the areas of data security and software infrastructure.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Prototype Fund Hardware</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://okfn.de/en/projekte/prototypefundhardware/"/>
    <id>https://okfn.de/en/projekte/prototypefundhardware/</id>
    <published>0001-01-01T00:00:00+0000</published>
    <updated>0001-01-01T00:00:00+0000</updated>
    <summary></summary>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Open administrative data</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://okfn.de/en/projekte/opendata/"/>
    <id>https://okfn.de/en/projekte/opendata/</id>
    <published>0001-01-01T00:00:00+0000</published>
    <updated>0001-01-01T00:00:00+0000</updated>
    <summary>&lt;p&gt;Public authorities from federal to local level produce and publish thousands of documents every day. In the context of the omnipresent digitalisation of public services, many goals have been set in recent years concerning the use of open data standards. However, the implementation fell short of the target so far. There is a great need for public authorities to build up knowledge and competences in the field of data provision. With this project the OKF wants to put its focus again on one of its core topics: contributing to the social discourse by offering our expertise in the field of open data.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>FragDenStaat</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://okfn.de/en/projekte/fragdenstaat/"/>
    <id>https://okfn.de/en/projekte/fragdenstaat/</id>
    <published>0001-01-01T00:00:00+0000</published>
    <updated>0001-01-01T00:00:00+0000</updated>
    <summary>&lt;p&gt;In a democracy, it is essential that citizens are able to freely access information about government actions. The Freedom of Information Act gives everyone the right to request documents from public authorities. With the online platform FragDenStaat, we support citizens in exercising their right to access information from German authorities. Citizens no longer have to wade through the jungle of federal and state laws to submit a request. Requests and responses are published transparently online. In the year the project was launched, the number of requests for information in Germany doubled.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Code for Germany</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://okfn.de/en/projekte/codeforde/"/>
    <id>https://okfn.de/en/projekte/codeforde/</id>
    <published>0001-01-01T00:00:00+0000</published>
    <updated>0001-01-01T00:00:00+0000</updated>
    <summary>&lt;p&gt;Code for Germany is a network of volunteers dedicated to a digital future that serves the common good. The network comprises approximately 300 community members in Germany and beyond. They examine the state of digitalization in their cities, municipalities, and regions. They develop helpful software and hardware projects. They analyze current technological developments for their societal benefits. They demonstrate the value of open data and advocate for the sustainable digitalization of public administration.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Jugend hackt</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://okfn.de/en/projekte/jugendhackt/"/>
    <id>https://okfn.de/en/projekte/jugendhackt/</id>
    <published>0001-01-01T00:00:00+0000</published>
    <updated>0001-01-01T00:00:00+0000</updated>
    <summary>&lt;p&gt;Improving the world with code – that has been the goal of Jugend hackt since 2013, a programme for young people between the ages of 12 and 18 who are interested in technology and want to explore how technology and society are connected. At Jugend hackt, we do code and tinker, of course, but we are interested in more than that. We want to teach responsible use of technology. For us, this includes exploring ethical hacking, but also the openness of code and data. Tech skills are more than just something that looks good on a CV.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>2030watch</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://okfn.de/en/projekte/2030-watch/"/>
    <id>https://okfn.de/en/projekte/2030-watch/</id>
    <published>0001-01-01T00:00:00+0000</published>
    <updated>0001-01-01T00:00:00+0000</updated>
    <summary>&lt;p&gt;2030Watch monitors the implementation of the Sustainable Development Goals (SDGs) in Germany.
The SDGs were set by the United Nations in September 2015 and will be implemented by 2030.
All members of the United Nations have committed to realising these 17 goals and 169 targets.
The goals include the eradication of poverty and inequality between and within countries, as well as action against climate change.
2030Watch primarily uses data from the OECD, the World Bank and other international organisations.
The project will also propose indicators for goals which are hard to operationalize, such as fair trade relations.
The launch of the 2030 Watch website is planned for the end of October 2015.
The project budget for 2015 is 55.620 Euro.
73% of the budget is funded by the German ministry for Economic Cooperation and Development.
The other funders are Welthungerhilfe (9%), Brot für die Welt/EED (9%) and Terre des Hommes (7%).
The remaining funds are private donations (below 1%).&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Alliance F5</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://okfn.de/en/projekte/buendnisf5/"/>
    <id>https://okfn.de/en/projekte/buendnisf5/</id>
    <published>0001-01-01T00:00:00+0000</published>
    <updated>0001-01-01T00:00:00+0000</updated>
    <summary>&lt;p&gt;Together with AlgorithmWatch, the Society for Civil Rights, Reporters Without Borders and Wikimedia Germany, we have joined forces in the F5 alliance to advocate for the concerns, ideas and demands of the digital civil society in Germany.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are united in the aspiration to ensure democratic digitization built on the pillars of openness and transparency, participation and access, protection of fundamental and human rights, and protection of consumer concerns. Our goal is to put the common good at the heart of digital policy and ensure the future of a democratic digital society. That&#39;s why we pool our expertise in the various topic areas of digitization.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Apps and the city</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://okfn.de/en/projekte/appsandthecity/"/>
    <id>https://okfn.de/en/projekte/appsandthecity/</id>
    <published>0001-01-01T00:00:00+0000</published>
    <updated>0001-01-01T00:00:00+0000</updated>
    <summary>&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Apps and the City&amp;rdquo; was a hackday on local traffic organised by Open Knowledge Foundation Germany together with the local transport provider VBB, the Berlin government, and the FH Potsdam.
The VBB released GTFS data, opened up their API and provided some geo datasets about entrances to stations.
During the event, coders, software experts, and designers used open transport data to create applications intended to improve public transport non-commercially.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Apps for Europe</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://okfn.de/en/projekte/appsforeurope/"/>
    <id>https://okfn.de/en/projekte/appsforeurope/</id>
    <published>0001-01-01T00:00:00+0000</published>
    <updated>0001-01-01T00:00:00+0000</updated>
    <summary>&lt;p&gt;Apps for Europe was a program intended to showcase the impact of open data in terms of its economic potential.
Neelie Kroes, former Vice President of the European Commission and a strong supporter of Apps for Europe, quantifies the value of open data at several billion euros.
The Consortium behind Apps for Europe wants to facilitate the exploration of the value of open data by helping entrepreneurs to transform their ideas into successful businesses that can gain foothold all over Europe.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>BIG</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://okfn.de/en/projekte/big/"/>
    <id>https://okfn.de/en/projekte/big/</id>
    <published>0001-01-01T00:00:00+0000</published>
    <updated>0001-01-01T00:00:00+0000</updated>
    <summary>&lt;p&gt;Big Data Public Private Forum (BIG) worked towards the definition and implementation of a clear strategy that tackles the necessary efforts in terms of research and innovation, while it also provided a major boost for technology adoption as well as supporting actions for the successful implementation of the Big Data economy.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Bundesgit</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://okfn.de/en/projekte/bundesgit/"/>
    <id>https://okfn.de/en/projekte/bundesgit/</id>
    <published>0001-01-01T00:00:00+0000</published>
    <updated>0001-01-01T00:00:00+0000</updated>
    <summary>&lt;p&gt;This git repository contains all German federal laws and regulations in markdown format. The XML version of these laws available on gesetze-im-internet.de serves as the source. With BundesGit the most current version of the laws is saved. This makes their historic development and adaptation transparent and easily comprehensible.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
