<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Open Knowledge Foundation DE</title>
  <link rel="self" href="https://okfn.de/en/projekte/atom.xml"/>
  <updated>1970-01-01T01:33:34+0100</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Open Knowledge Foundation DE</name>
    <email>info@okfn.de</email>
    <uri>https://okfn.de</uri>
  </author>
  <id>https://okfn.de</id>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Open Gov Netzwerk</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://okfn.de/en/projekte/ogp/"/>
    <id>https://okfn.de/en/projekte/ogp/</id>
    <published>0001-01-01T00:00:00+0000</published>
    <updated>0001-01-01T00:00:00+0000</updated>
    <summary>As part of the Open Government Network, we support Germany&amp;rsquo;s active participation in the Open Government Partnership (OGP) and the interests of German civil society in this process, as well as help coordinate this civil society network.
The network is an association of civil society organisations and individuals that has been working since 2011 to promote open government and administrative action as a holistic approach to strengthening democracy. In particular, the focus is on the exchange with the Federal Government and the development of national action plans.</summary>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Turing-Bus</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://okfn.de/en/projekte/turing-bus/"/>
    <id>https://okfn.de/en/projekte/turing-bus/</id>
    <published>0001-01-01T00:00:00+0000</published>
    <updated>0001-01-01T00:00:00+0000</updated>
    <summary>The Turing Bus is a mobile educational project for schools and youth clubs in rural areas. The bus brings representatives of Fablabs, OK-Labs and Hackspaces as well as experts in digital topics to often underserved places of youth education. Its goal is to generate an exchange of knowledge and experiences through workshops, discussions, screenings, and more. The project is funded in the Science Year of the BMBF.
The Bus wants to explore, discuss, and critically question the role of digitisation and technology in the professional landscape and society as a whole.</summary>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Code for Germany</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://okfn.de/en/projekte/codeforde/"/>
    <id>https://okfn.de/en/projekte/codeforde/</id>
    <published>0001-01-01T00:00:00+0000</published>
    <updated>0001-01-01T00:00:00+0000</updated>
    <summary>Code For Germany is a network of groups of volunteers (labs) who use their skills to shape their cities and social life. They advocate more transparency, open data and participation in their cities. In particular, they mediate between civil society, administration and politics, and use their skills to improve communication between them. This provides the necessary impetus so that as many people as possible can benefit from open and free digitisation.</summary>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>FragDenStaat</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://okfn.de/en/projekte/fragdenstaat/"/>
    <id>https://okfn.de/en/projekte/fragdenstaat/</id>
    <published>0001-01-01T00:00:00+0000</published>
    <updated>0001-01-01T00:00:00+0000</updated>
    <summary>In a democracy, it is necessary for citizens to be able to inform themselves freely about government actions. With the Freedom of Information Act, every person, regardless of age or origin, has the right to request documents from the authorities. The FragDenStaat online platform supports citizens in exercising their right to access information from German authorities. Citizens no longer have to work their way through the legal jungle of the federal states and the federal government to make a request.</summary>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Prototype Fund</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://okfn.de/en/projekte/prototypefund/"/>
    <id>https://okfn.de/en/projekte/prototypefund/</id>
    <published>0001-01-01T00:00:00+0000</published>
    <updated>0001-01-01T00:00:00+0000</updated>
    <summary>The Prototype Fund supports socially relevant software projects and increases their sustainable impact by open sourcing as a principle. In short: We support Public Interest Tech.
We make digital-social innovation possible with developers that bring a wide range of skills in technology design. With up to 47,500 euros per project and team, the Prototype Fund supports software developers, hackers and creatives in building protptypes for tools and applications in the areas of civic tech, data literacy, IT security and software infrastructure.</summary>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Datenschule</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://okfn.de/en/projekte/datenschule/"/>
    <id>https://okfn.de/en/projekte/datenschule/</id>
    <published>0001-01-01T00:00:00+0000</published>
    <updated>0001-01-01T00:00:00+0000</updated>
    <summary>The Data School is a nationwide educational program on the subject of data and technologies. We mainly target non-profit organisations that work with data, or alternatively want to deepen their existing data knowledge. Within a cooperation period of about three months, we developed practice-oriented workshops and individualized technical training courses with our partners and trainers to support social projects.
We want non-profit organisations:
 to encourage targeted use of data and technology in their work.</summary>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Jugend hackt</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://okfn.de/en/projekte/jugendhackt/"/>
    <id>https://okfn.de/en/projekte/jugendhackt/</id>
    <published>0001-01-01T00:00:00+0000</published>
    <updated>0001-01-01T00:00:00+0000</updated>
    <summary>Jugend hackt is a program for young people who want to improve the world with their technical skills. Supported by volunteer mentors, our participants develop digital tools, prototypes and concepts for a better future. Our offer includes hackathon events in many cities, regional labs, an online community and international exchange programs.
In line with our motto &amp;ldquo;Improve the world with code&amp;rdquo;, Jugend hackt is about more than just learning to program: We understand technology as a means of social change.</summary>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Zugang gestalten</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://okfn.de/en/projekte/zuganggestalten/"/>
    <id>https://okfn.de/en/projekte/zuganggestalten/</id>
    <published>1970-01-01T01:33:34+0100</published>
    <updated>1970-01-01T01:33:34+0100</updated>
    <summary>Museums, archives, libraries and momuments are operated and maintained with public funds. The international conference &amp;ldquo;Zugang gestalten&amp;rdquo; asks the question whether this is adequately reflected in the level of access to the cultural treasures that these institutions possess and maintain. The conference invites key figures in culture, science, civic society and politics to publicly explore different ways of accessing digital cultural heritage in Germany.
&amp;ldquo;Zugang gestalten&amp;rdquo; stands under the auspices of the German UNESCO commission and is a collaboartive project of the Open Knowledge Foundation Deutschland, Stiftung Historische Museen Hamburg, Servicestelle Digitalisierung Berlin, Deutschen Digitalen Bibliothek, Internet &amp;amp; Gesellschaft Collaboratory, Institut Français Deutschland, iRights.</summary>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>2030watch</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://okfn.de/en/projekte/2030-watch/"/>
    <id>https://okfn.de/en/projekte/2030-watch/</id>
    <published>0001-01-01T00:00:00+0000</published>
    <updated>0001-01-01T00:00:00+0000</updated>
    <summary>2030Watch monitors the implementation of the Sustainable Development Goals (SDGs) in Germany. The SDGs were set by the United Nations in September 2015 and will be implemented by 2030. All members of the United Nations have committed to realising these 17 goals and 169 targets. The goals include the eradication of poverty and inequality between and within countries, as well as action against climate change. 2030Watch primarily uses data from the OECD, the World Bank and other international organisations.</summary>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Apps and the city</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://okfn.de/en/projekte/appsandthecity/"/>
    <id>https://okfn.de/en/projekte/appsandthecity/</id>
    <published>0001-01-01T00:00:00+0000</published>
    <updated>0001-01-01T00:00:00+0000</updated>
    <summary>&amp;ldquo;Apps and the City&amp;rdquo; was a hackday on local traffic organised by Open Knowledge Foundation Germany together with the local transport provider VBB, the Berlin government, and the FH Potsdam. The VBB released GTFS data, opened up their API and provided some geo datasets about entrances to stations. During the event, coders, software experts, and designers used open transport data to create applications intended to improve public transport non-commercially.</summary>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Apps for Europe</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://okfn.de/en/projekte/appsforeurope/"/>
    <id>https://okfn.de/en/projekte/appsforeurope/</id>
    <published>0001-01-01T00:00:00+0000</published>
    <updated>0001-01-01T00:00:00+0000</updated>
    <summary>Apps for Europe was a program intended to showcase the impact of open data in terms of its economic potential. Neelie Kroes, former Vice President of the European Commission and a strong supporter of Apps for Europe, quantifies the value of open data at several billion euros. The Consortium behind Apps for Europe wants to facilitate the exploration of the value of open data by helping entrepreneurs to transform their ideas into successful businesses that can gain foothold all over Europe.</summary>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>BIG</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://okfn.de/en/projekte/big/"/>
    <id>https://okfn.de/en/projekte/big/</id>
    <published>0001-01-01T00:00:00+0000</published>
    <updated>0001-01-01T00:00:00+0000</updated>
    <summary>Big Data Public Private Forum (BIG) worked towards the definition and implementation of a clear strategy that tackles the necessary efforts in terms of research and innovation, while it also provided a major boost for technology adoption as well as supporting actions for the successful implementation of the Big Data economy.</summary>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Bundesgit</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://okfn.de/en/projekte/bundesgit/"/>
    <id>https://okfn.de/en/projekte/bundesgit/</id>
    <published>0001-01-01T00:00:00+0000</published>
    <updated>0001-01-01T00:00:00+0000</updated>
    <summary>This git repository contains all German federal laws and regulations in markdown format. The XML version of these laws available on gesetze-im-internet.de serves as the source. With BundesGit the most current version of the laws is saved. This makes their historic development and adaptation transparent and easily comprehensible.</summary>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Coding da Vinci</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://okfn.de/en/projekte/codingdavinci/"/>
    <id>https://okfn.de/en/projekte/codingdavinci/</id>
    <published>0001-01-01T00:00:00+0000</published>
    <updated>0001-01-01T00:00:00+0000</updated>
    <summary>Coding da Vinci is the first cultural data hackathon in Germany that brings together cultural heritage institutions and the hacker/designer community to develop ideas and prototypes for both the cultural sector and the public. More and more galleries, libraries, archives, and museums (GLAMs) are digitalising their collections to make them accessible online and to preserve our heritage for future generations. Only when cultural data is made openly available (according to the Open Definition) can it serve as the creative basis for innovative new applications and projects.</summary>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>D-EITI</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://okfn.de/en/projekte/eiti/"/>
    <id>https://okfn.de/en/projekte/eiti/</id>
    <published>0001-01-01T00:00:00+0000</published>
    <updated>0001-01-01T00:00:00+0000</updated>
    <summary>The global Extractive Industries Transparency Initiative (EITI) advocates greater financial transparency and accountability in the extractive sector.
The initiative, which was founded in 2003 as part of the 2002 Sustainability Summit in Johannesburg, South Africa, is based on close cooperation between governments, companies and civil society in over 50 countries. They disclose information on tax payments, licenses, production volumes and other important data relating to the extraction of oil, gas and mineral resources.</summary>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
