<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>TopfSecret on OKF</title>
    <link>https://okfn.de/tags/topfsecret/</link>
    <description>Recent content in TopfSecret on OKF</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>de</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 15 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://okfn.de/tags/topfsecret/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Pot Secret - Freeing thousands of Food Safety Reports</title>
      <link>https://okfn.de/blog/2019/01/pot-secret/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://okfn.de/blog/2019/01/pot-secret/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday we launched &amp;ldquo;Pot Secret&amp;rdquo; (&amp;ldquo;Topf Secret&amp;rdquo; in German) - a platform against secrecy at food authorities. Consumers can use this platform to obtain the results of food safety inspections in restaurants, bakeries, supermarkets and other food-processing businesses.
Together with our partner foodwatch, we created a platform that enables all people to quickly and easily send pre-formulated freedom of information requests about businesses to the relevant authorities.
&amp;ldquo;Pot Secret&amp;rdquo; is based on a map that displays all food-related businesses that can be found in OpenStreetMap.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Jetzt mitmachen: Topf Secret!</title>
      <link>https://okfn.de/blog/2019/01/topf-secret/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://okfn.de/blog/2019/01/topf-secret/</guid>
      <description>Heute launchen wir gemeinsam mit foodwatch „Topf Secret“ – eine Plattform gegen Geheimniskrämerei bei Lebensmittelbehörden. Auf ihr können Verbraucher*innen Ergebnisse von Hygienekontrollen in Restaurants, Bäckereien, Supermärkten &amp;amp; Co. abfragen.
Zur Plattform: Hier entlang →
Die Plattform ermöglicht es allen Menschen, einfach und schnell vorformulierte Anfragen zur Hygiene von Lebensmittelbetrieben an die zuständigen Behörden zu schicken. Die halten bisher die allermeisten Ergebnisse von Hygienekontrollen geheim.
Seit Jahren wird jeder vierte kontrollierte Betrieb beanstandet, größtenteils wegen Hygienemängeln.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
